https://www.uclan.ac.uk/corporate_information/website-cookies-policy.php

Open Days
Why UCLan?
Vice-Chancellor's Group
Honorary fellowsInternational Honorary FellowsMission and values
Academic Quality and Enhancement
Complaints ProcedureModern SlaveryFree Speech, Equality & Inclusion
More
Why UCLan?
Website and Cookies Policy
Here at the University of Central Lancashire (UCLan) we take your privacy very seriously and are fully committed to safeguarding and protecting the privacy of our website users. By accessing and using our websites or other services, without changing your internet settings, we will assume you are happy to accept our cookie policy as outlined below.
This policy explains how we collect, use and handle information that you provide through your use of the University of Central Lancashire (UCLan) website. We utilise this data to respond to your enquiries, monitor use of our systems, and to improve your experience of our website.
All personal data collected and used by UCLan is handled in compliance with current data protection legislation. If you would like more detailed information relating to our Data Protection Policy, your privacy or your rights, or who to contact if you have any concerns about the use of your data, please visit our Privacy Policy.
This policy is reviewed on a regular basis and any changes will be updated accordingly on this page. This page was last updated in May 2018.
Introduction to Cookies +
Introduction to Cookies
In addition to the collection, retention and use of directly provided personal information, the University utilises 'cookies' to store and retrieve anonymous data during each visit to the website.
It is important for you to understand what cookies are, what we use cookies for, and how to disable them if you do not wish for them to be used whilst visiting this site.
Please note we are currently developing our cookie tools to allow web users to easily change their cookie settings. Please check back for updates, which will appear in due course.
When you access our website or officially recognised microsites, we use cookies to give you the best possible experience on our website and help improve our services to you. For example, we may use cookies to:
Make the website work properly and enable you to use the services we provide.
Collect data on how visitors use our websites so that we can improve our site and functionality and provide an enjoyable experience.
Remember your preferences, making the site easier and more intuitive for you.
Target or advertise our other services you may be interested in, through third party cookies.
What are Cookies ? +
What Are Cookies ?
A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer or device by websites that you visit. Cookies are widely used in order to enhance websites, providing a more tailored and personal experience whilst permitting websites to review and analyse anonymous information about visitors (e.g., time spent on particular pages). Some of these cookies are presented by us, some of the cookies are presented by third-parties such as Google, YouTube, Facebook and Twitter. A cookie does not identify the individual viewing a web page and does not give us access to your computer. Further information about cookies can be found at www.allaboutcookies.org.
Managing Cookies +
Managing Cookies
We would like you to accept the cookies we serve, however we appreciate you may not want to do so.
Nearly all browsers allow you to update and change your options and cookie settings – which you can find out further information using the links below:
Microsoft Internet Explorer
Mozilla Firefox
Google Chrome
Safari and iOS
Please be aware that by disabling some cookies, a number of important web functions and services on our site may not operate effectively - which will affect your experience on our site. You may also block third party cookies used by our advertisers; however you may still receive advertisements, these will just not be tailored to your likes and interests. You can find out more via Your Online Choices.
Types of Cookies +
Types of cookies
Cookies may be set either by uclan.ac.uk (“first party cookies”) or by third party websites (“third party cookies”). Cookies may be used or required for a number of reasons:
Essential cookies
Essential cookies enable the website to function correctly and are required to provide access to secure sections of the website (e.g., when you log in to staff or student areas). If you do not permit access to and use of such cookies then you may not be able to log in correctly.
Functionality cookies
Functionality cookies are used to enhance your experience of using our website. They remember the choices users make and provide a more personalised service.
Analytics & Advertising cookies
Third-party analytic cookies are used to collect anonymous information about how visitors use our website. This may include how long you stay, what pages you visits, what you click on and what country you are accessing our site from. We analyse such data to help improve the content of the site and to aid us in investigating issues such as missing pages. The main tools we use for this are Google Analytics and Site improve. You can opt out of these cookies without affecting your user experience of the website.
We also make use of tracking cookies for advertising and remarketing purposes as well as to measure the performance and effectiveness of our online marketing and recruitment campaigns. We use this information and cookies to make advertising more relevant to you.
The following tables identify the cookies we use on our site and explains the purpose of each cookie.
Cookie
Name
Purpose
uclan.ac.uk
gdpr-basic
We set this cookie to remember your preferences to our cookie policy notice
Google & Google Universal Analytics
We use Google Tag Manager to track and manage other cookies used.
_ga
_utmz
_utmc
_utmb
_utma
_qca
_utmt
_gat
_gid
CONSENT
collect*
NID**
Ads/ga-audiences***
We use Google Analytics cookies to understand how users browse our website in order to make it a better browsing experience for everyone. These are set across the UCLan web site to allow us to see how websites are being used and improve them, thereby improving the service provided to the user.
*A session cookie used to send data to GA about visitors device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.
** Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user's device and remembers preferences.
***Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor's online behaviour across websites.
YouTube
GPS
PREF*
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE*
YSC
A functional cookie, these are set across the UCLan web services to enable additional elements to be displayed. These cookies are set by the YouTube video service on pages with embedded YouTube video. A third party cookie, this expires at the end of your session, except for those marked * which are eight months
Twitter
personalization_id
A functional cookie, these are set across the UCLan web services to enable additional elements to display. This allows us to embed Twitter feeds from our official channels.
Facebook Pixel
Tr
tf
A third-party cookie used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertising products. Allows measurement, optimising and building of audiences for advertising served on Facebook.
Interest Based Advertising Cookies
RadiumOne via gwallet.com
ra1_sid
ra1_pd
ra1_sgm
RA1balancer
ra1_uid
R1/pixel/
Mc
Our key advertising partners and associated cookies are listed below.
Interest based advertising cookies and tracking technologies are used are used to collect information about website usage and interaction with targeting and service.
*Some cookies will be first used to check the user’s browser supports cookies.
We use Google Tag Manager to track and manage other cookies used.
Please note, we review the following information and our use of particular cookies on a regular basis. The tables below represent a review of cookies as of May 2018. If you find a cookie set whilst browsing our website that is not mentioned here then please contact us and we will investigate thoroughly and update this page accordingly.
University System & Service Cookies +
University System & Service Cookies
Cookie
Name
Purpose
www.uclan.ac.uk
cookie_accept, cookie_decline
Acknowledgement of cookie banner and link to cookie/privacy policy
www.uclan.ac.uk
course_cookie
Stores details of the last course page visited
UCLan (Netscalar)
NSC_ESNS
Balances visitor load on UCLan servers
careerhub.uclan.ac.uk
ASP.NET_SessionId, _RequestVerificationToken
Session cookie for login verification
intranet.uclan.ac.uk
NSC_WT*
Session cookie for login verification
roombooking.uclan.ac.uk
ASP.NET_SessionId, KeepPortalHidden
Session cookies for online Room Booking System
shibidp.uclan.ac.uk
shibboleth.ebscohost.com
(Shibboleth)
JSESSIONID, _idp_authn_lc_key
BIGipServershib-wildcard_port
Login and verification for Shibboleth
vls.uclan.ac.uk
NSC_WT-*
Session cookie for login verification (UCLan Video Library Server)
www2.uclan.ac.uk
PHPSESSID
Session cookie for Virtual Placement Circuit (NHS)
atoz.ebsco.com
ASP.NET_SessionId, AtoZAuthCookie, BIGipServerpool_AtoZ_http, Ebsco.Translations
Login and verification for EBSCO
Achiever Interactive Software
T_SessionId
Creates a session ID used by our online booking software for events such as our Open Day and Applicant Days.
Logs and Search Engines +
Logs and Search Engines
All University of Central Lancashire’s web server activity is recorded. We use our server log files to analyse usage of the University website and associated systems for resourcing and planning purposes. This information may be archived in an anonymous form for historical records for a defined period of time only.
The University of Central Lancashire makes use of two search engines: the widely-used general Google Custom Search and a course-specific search engine. We collect and retain search data in order to analyse visitor requests. We use this information to prioritise popular and important content to ensure relevant search results are provided.
Surveys +
Surveys
From time to time we will facilitate the presentation of surveys on the website. Privacy information and use of cookies will be detailed by each survey and will supersede or supplement policy presented here.
Limit of this Policy +
Limit of this policy
This privacy policy applies only to websites administered by the University of Central Lancashire which reside on the main UCLan domain (www.uclan.ac.uk) and officially recognised UCLan microsites. While this website provides links to other relevant websites, the University cannot be held responsible for the content provided by third-party websites or providers and is not responsible for the privacy policies and protection of your data collected by these websites.
Contact Us - UCLan's Information Governance Manager +
Contact Us - UCLan’s Information Governance Manager
UCLan’s Information Governance Manager is the designated Data Protection Officer and deals with all matters relating to data protection legislation and the Freedom of Information Act 2000, as well as managing and coordinating requests for information received by the University. You can contact the Information Governance Manager at:
Information Governance Manager
Office of the University Secretary and Legal Officer
Harris Building
University of Central Lancashire
Preston
Lancashire
PR1 2HE
Email: DPFOIA@uclan.ac.uk
Telephone: +44 (0)1772 892561
ICO registration
UCLan acts as a data controller and a data processor and processes personal data in both capacities. As such, UCLan is registered with the independent regulator, the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). The ICO is the lead supervisory authority for UCLan and its subsidiaries.
The general purposes for which UCLan processes personal data can be seen in its register entry, which is publically available on the ICO’s website. UCLan’s registration number is Z5512420. Further information about how UCLan ensures it processes personal data in compliance with data protection legislation can be found in its Data Protection Policy.
Corporate Information
Board of Governors
Vice-Chancellor's Group
Honorary fellowsInternational Honorary FellowsMission and values
Complaints ProcedureModern SlaveryFree Speech, Equality & Inclusion
Widening Participation & Access
Fundraising
UCLan
Preston,
Hey there, we use Cookies!
We use cookies to give you the best possible experience on our website, help improve our
services, provide social media features, and assist in our marketing efforts.
Yes, I'm fine with this. Let's go!
Cookie Policy & Settings
